这是二零二三年河北省初中毕业生
升学文化课考试英语试卷听力部分。
听力部分共有五道题，第一题至第四题为选择题，
第五题为填空题。
做题时，先将答案答在试卷上，在听力测试结束后，再将答案填涂到答题
卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
是因到此结束。
第一题：听句子，选出句子中所包含的信息。
下面你将听到五个句子，每个句子读两遍。
请你听完句子的第二遍朗读后，从每小题所给出的
,B Boys and girls, let's begin our class.
三个选项。
中，选出包含所听信息的选项。
Grandma, can I cook some noodles for you now?
Listen, the sun is so beautiful.
Dear friends, I'm here to introduce my hometown,
Your brother will play with you after school, Amy.
第二题：听句子，选出该句的最佳答语。
下面你将听到五个句子，每个句子读两遍，请你听完。
完句子的第二遍朗读后，从每小题所给出的
,B Which cup is yours,
三个选项中，选出该句的最佳答语。
7. Oh, it's really cold today, mom.
8. Sally, do you think Michael will come on time?
9. How was your holiday in Hangzhou, Jenny?
10. What is the most polite way to ask Mr.
to check your writing?
第三题，听对。
对话和问题选择正确答案。
下面你将听到四组对话和八个问题，
每组对话和问题读两遍。
请你听完对话和问题的第二遍朗读后，从每小题所给出的
,B Cindy, there's a phone call for you.
三个选项中选出正确答案。
请听第一组对话，回答第十一题。
请听第二组对话，回答第十二题。
请听第三组对话，回答第十三至十五题。
Hello, this is David.
Who's that speaking?
It's Dan. Is Cindy there?
I've called her three times, but she didn't answer.
Oh, she's quite busy today.
She's having a meeting now.
But I have something important to tell her.
Can I take a message?
thank you. tell her to hand in her report this morning.
Let me write it down.
in the report this morning.
That's right. Oh, hold on please.
She started walking out of the meeting room.
Cindy, there's a phone call for you.
Who is answering the telephone?
How is Cindy today?
Question number fifteen.
What does Dan ask Cindy to do?
请听第四组对话，回答第十六至十八。
May I ask you a question, Miss White?
Sure, Jack. What is it?
What does the word return mean in this sentence?
Did you look it up in a dictionary?
Not yet. Well, let's do it together.
Oh, there are so many meanings here.
I don't know which one to choose.
Read the sentence again and then you'll get it.
Well, it means go back, guess.
Quite right. You see, a dictionary is helpful.
Yeah, thanks, Miss White.
I'll return to my seat right now.
Good for you, my boy.
May I ask you a question, Miss White?
Sure, Jack. What is it?
What does the word return mean in this sentence?
Did you look it up in a dictionary?
Not yet. Well, let's do it together.
there are so many meanings here.
I don't know which one to choose.
Read the sentence again and then you'll get it.
Well, it means go back, I guess.
Quite right. You see, a dictionary is helpful.
Yeah, thanks, Miss White.
I'll return to my seat right now.
Good for you, my boy.
number 16. What does Jack ask Miss White to do?
does Jack ask Miss White to do?
Question number 17.
How does Miss White help Jack?
Question number 18.
What will Jack do next?
第四题：听短文和问题，选择正确答案。
下面你将听到两篇短文和七个问题，
每篇短文和问题读两遍。
请你听完短文和问题的第二遍朗读后，根据。
我听内容，从每小题所给出的
三个选项中选出正确答案。
请听第一篇短文，回答第十九至二十一题。
Tom, this is Peter.
I'm telling you that I'll be a little late for the party.
I feel sorry, but I have to finish my homework first.
It can be done at about 7 o And then I'll go to the party by bus.
It may take me 20 minutes to get there.
Oh, one more thing.
I'll bring some cookies to the party.
I hope you'll like them.
See you then.
Hey, Tom, this is Peter.
I'm telling you that I'll be a little late for the party.
I feel sorry, but I have to finish my homework first.
It can be done at about 7 o And then I'll go to the party by bus.
It may take me 20 minutes to get there.
Oh, one more thing.
I'll bring some cookies to the party.
I hope you'll like them.
See you then.
Question number 19.
Why will Peter be late for the party?
Question number 20.
How long may it Peter to get there by bus?
Question number 21.
What will Peter bring to the party?
请听第二篇短文，回答第二十二至二十五题。
Welcome to the English Club.
My name is Lucy, and I am your teacher today.
Now I'd like to talk about today's activity.
At 2 o in the afternoon, you will start work in small groups in the East Hall.
We'll have 8 groups, and there will be 6 students in each group.
Each group will write a short play in English.
It must be about a famous person in history of China.
At 3 o 'clock, you will act out your play in the West Hall.
We'll invite some foreign students in our school to watch the plays.
The activity will be over at about 4 o
I hope you enjoy it.
Welcome to the English Club.
My name is Lucy, and I am your teacher today.
Now I'd like to talk about today's activity.
At 2 o in the afternoon, you will start work in small groups in the East Hall.
We'll have 8 groups, and there will be 6 students in each group.
Each group will write a short play in English.
It must be about a famous person in the history of China.
At 3 o 'clock, you will act out your play in the West Hall.
We'll invite some foreign students in our school to watch the plays.
The activity will be over at about 4 o I hope you enjoy it.
When will the students start to in groups?
Question 23. How many students will each group have?
Question 24. What will they do in the West Hall?
Question 25. Who will be invited to watch the plays?
第五题，听短文填空。
下面你将听到一篇短文，短文读两遍。
请你听完短文的第二遍朗读后，根据短文的内容和提示，在信息表中相应
的横线上填入所缺信息。
Hello everybody. We'll have a practice this Friday.
Now I need to tell you what to do.
The fire practice will start at 10 o in the morning.
When you hear the bell, get up from your chair, but you mustn't run anywhere.
Don't carry anything with you.
I mean, leave all the things where they are.
Be sure to cover your mouth and nose, and then follow the signs to the nearest door.
You must move out of the building quickly and quietly.
Remember not to take the
Finally, we'll meet at the park behind the building.
OK? Got it?
Hello everybody. We'll have a fire practice this Friday.
Now I need to tell you what to do.
The fire practice will start at 10 o in the morning.
When you hear the bell, get up from your chair, but you mustn't run anywhere.
Don't carry anything with you.
I mean, leave all the things where they are.
Be sure to cover your mouth and nose, and then follow the signs to the nearest door.
You must move out of the building quickly and quietly.
Remember not to take the lift.
Finally, we'll meet at the park behind the building.
OK? Got it?
Thank you for watching.